Parker Satterfield

E: parkers205@gmail.com

C: 205-515-6771

GitHub: parkersatterfield

Summary

I am currently seeking a role as a Software Engineer. After graduating from Auburn University in 2019 with a degree in Biological Systems Engineering, I worked as an engineering consultant in Atlanta for two years before moving back home to Birmingham. In November of 2020, I started a company, Dibs Funding, with the goal of connecting the startup community in a way that provided both entertainment and fundraising tools. Though I have known how to program since I was in high school, my experience building Dibs is where I was first introduced to the world of web development. I developed the MVP for Dibs and found a new passion for designing web apps. While working on my startup, I enrolled in Georgia Tech's Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp, and I am now seeking a full-time position as an engineer for a company in my hometown of Birmingham. I am 24 years old, career-driven, hard-working, and have an entrepreneurial spirit.

Education

Georgia Tech Bootcamps 2021 Full Stack Web Development

Auburn University 2015-2019 Bachelors of Biosystems Engineering Minor in Business

Skills

- UI/UX design and wireframing
- TDD specifically using Jest
- API creation and routing for multi-page and single-page apps
- Improving SEO and accessibility
- Working proficiency with Microsoft Office suite
- Working proficiency in a team environment with version control tools such as Git and GitHub
- Technical writing

Technologies

- MERN Stack
- GraphQL
- Popular JavaScript libraries such as React, jQuery, Moment.js, etc.
- Node.js and popular npm packages such as bcrypt, express, and express-handlebars.
- Basic web development languages such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Popular CSS frameworks such as Bootstrap and Materialize
- Databases: MySQL, MongoDB
- Cloud service platforms: *Heroku, Netlify, Github Pages*

Work History

Founder, Dibs Funding, LLC 2021-Present

Founded and created a social networking and fundraising web-app to provide early stage startups and startup ideas with a platform to blog, receive feedback, and raise money to fund the upfront costs of starting a company

Project Engineer, Keck & Wood, Inc. 2019-2021 Worked on various infrastructure projects including water treatment plant design, roadway design, flood management, and city planning

Research Assistant, Auburn University 2018-2019
Worked under Dr. Lauren Beckingham to write a Matlab program that used machine learning to identify minerality in a 3D CT image from a 2D training image

Projects



Dibs Funding startup project built with Bubble.io



Personal Portfolio
My portfolio site built
with React



Reloc8
Bootcamp project
that utilizes Yelp API

References

References available upon request. Thank you!